JAMES KOMO

www.github.com/jameskomo www.linkedin.com/in/jameskomo Nairobi, Kenya (+254) 724 780529 james.komoh@gmail.com

www.jameskomo.com

Personal Statement

I am passionate about technology; the ability to not only create but be part of a bigger solution to world challenges.

Highlighted Software Applications

Communication Microservice- Team Lead, Full Stack Software Engineer

Year: 2019

Stack: Dramatiq Task Processor, Redis Server, Django REST, Twilio & Sendgrid API

URL: https://github.com/jameskomo/mookh-admin/tree/mookh-admin/scheduling

This application was a challenge given by Mookh Africa as part of final project at Moringa school. We worked on a Microservice based on Python Django and Android that orchestrates Mookh's SMS and Email communications allowing single platform integration with full-fledged scheduling capabilities.

- Set up Redis server for message brokering and integrated application with Dramatiq for SMS task queuing and processing
- Integrated application with Twilio SMS API as a communication backend
- Database Design-I created the PostgreSQL SMS model to support SMS API creation through Django REST framework for collaboration with Android Developer.

Multi-Banks Calculator - Scrum Master, Full Stack Software Engineer

Year: 2019

Stack: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ¡Query

URL: https://jameskomo.github.io/banks-loans-calculator/

This application allows users to view loan products and compare across various banks for the cheapest and most flexible terms.

- Designed the backend logic and implemented application backend functionalities
- Managed project team to ensure timely delivery and quality assurance

<u>NewsHighlight</u>

Year: 2019

Tech Stack: Python Flask, PostgreSQL, Heroku

URL: https://komo-news-highlight.herokuapp.com/

This is a Python Flask Application that allows users list and preview news articles from various sources. It consumes Newsapi.org API Key to collate news from various sources and users can visit the specific news links to read more.

Mtaa Watch Year: 2019

Tech Stack: Python Django, PostgreSQL, Heroku

URL: https://komo-neighborhood-watch.herokuapp.com/

This is a Python application based on Django framework that allows you to be in the loop about everything happening in your neighborhood. From contact information of different handyman to meeting announcements or even alerts.

Web Scraper
Year: 2019

Tech Stack: Python3.6, BeautifulSoup and Requests Libraries

URL: https://github.com/jameskomo/web-scraper

This is a web crawler that scrapers Reddit website for Data Science related articles.

Technical Skills

1. Strong

PostgreSQL, SQLite, REST APIs, JSON, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap4.0, JavaScript, AJAX, jQuery, Python-Django Framework, Git, GitHub, Linux, Netlify, Heroku, TDD, Containerization, ngrok, nginx, Docker, Scrum

2. Learning & Improving
Node IS Express IS ReactIS Flask

Node JS, Express JS, ReactJS, Flask, Angular, Jasmine Testing, AWS Cloud, MongoDB

Academic Background & Professional Training

Facebook-Andela Core Web Developer Training

August 2019-Nov 2019

- Agile Project Management and SCRUM
- Build Web Apps with ReactJS
- Create Simple Prototypes with Wireframes
- Build Your Web Projects With REST APIs
- Go Full-Stack With Node.js, Express, and MongoDB
- Retrieve Data Using SQL
- Secure Your Web Application With OWASP
- Test Your Website's Interface with Jasmine Framework
- Implementing Relational Databases with SQL
- Learn Programming With JavaScript

Moringa School

February 2019-June 2019

Immersive Software Engineering Boot Camp, Full Stack Specialization (Python, Flask, Django, SQL DBs, Angular, JavaScript, jQuery)

Spire Education

November 2014-Jan 2015

Career Accelerator Program Trainee

An intensive professional skills program based on the best education models around the world. Designed to ensure graduates are successful in the 21st century work world.

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology, Nairobi January 2008- Jul 2011 Bachelor of Science in Information Technology (BSc.IT)

Experience

DevOps Engineer: Atlancis Technologies

September 2019-Date

Software development, testing and deployment using technologies for developing automated CI/
CD pipelines with DevOps tools.

Knowledge and Bid Management Lead: Seven Seas Technologies October 2016-Jan 2019

- Scoped and successfully responded to bids worth at least 45m USD.
- Defined knowledge management structure for over 10 departments that boosted productivity by up to 30%.
- Established and published policies and policies for over 10 departments.

•

Business Development Executive: Attain Enterprise Solutions Limited, April 2015-Sept 2016

- I was responsible for the maximization of sales for Attain's products. I helped in the turnover of sales and provide data regarding changes required in the product to meet customer standards.
- Tapped into new markets through tendering and product demos leading to 5% market growth.
- Established business continuity plan that led to sales growth by over 10% based on deals closed.

Assistant Manager, Naivas Supermarkets Ltd

Mar 2012 – *Mar* 2014

Interests

- 1. Volunteerism-Volunteer Program Manager: Peace Ambassadors Integration Organization March 2014-Dec 2017
- 2. Technology- Member of Facebook Developer Circles and Andela Training.